Joe (Xiaozhou) Cui

CONTACT

Email info@joesdemosite.com

Phone 0452618869

Address Sunnybank Hills, QLD 4109
Portfolio https://www.joesdemosite.com

GitHub https://github.com/XiaozhouCui

CAREER SUMMARY

I am a talented full stack web developer, with more than 2 years of commercial experience.

I am looking to work in a place where I can make good use of my expertise. More importantly, I wish to work in projects where I have the opportunity to learn and apply the latest technology stacks.

Before changing my career in 2018, I had worked in the oil and gas industry for more than 8 years as a professional engineer. I have developed plenty of transferrable skills such as problem solving, communication skills and time management, and I am bilingual in English and Chinese.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer (Jan 2019 - Present)

BPA Analytics (Brisbane)

Duty: Develop, maintain and upgrade eSurveys for data collection. Develop new projects and features to facilitate data collection. Technology stack: React, Redux, TypeScript, Node/Express, MongoDB, SQL Server, Sass, AWS, Python, C#, VBS and many more.

Web Developer (2018 - 2019)

JR Academy (Brisbane).

Duty: Working in an agile environment, I was involved in the development and maintenance of JR Academy's official website and other products, mainly using Node.js (Keystone and koa), React (AntD) and Redux.

Process Safety Engineer (2015 - 2018)

Huahai Safety Science

Duty: Process safety analysis and risk management for oil refineries and chemical processing plants.

Process Engineer (2011 - 2015)

Worley

Duty: Process engineering design in the oil and gas industry. I worked in project-oriented and multi-disciplinary teams across the Asia-Pacific region, including Brisbane, Beijing and KL.

EDUCATION

Diploma of Web Development (top student in my class)

TAFE Queensland - Web Development

Master of Engineering (1st class Honours)

University of Auckland (NZ) - Chemical and Materials Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering

University of Canterbury (NZ) - Chemical and Process Engineering

KEY SKILLS WITH PROJECT EXAMPLES

- React and Redux: highly experienced in both React Hooks and class-based components. Proficient in related libraries including react-router-dom, redux-thunk and axios etc. Example of my recent eCommerce project: https://proshop888.herokuapp.com/
- Node.js and Express: strong working knowledge of writing REST APIs to perform authentication, authorisation and CRUD operations. Good understanding of middleware-based, asynchronous JavaScript. Node project deployed on AWS: http://natours-env.eba-nf9b3ubt.ap-southeast-2.elasticbeanstalk.com/
- > SQL Database: competent in both SQL Server and MySQL, experience varies from data modelling all the way to daily maintenance.
- NoSQL Database: advanced MongoDB / Mongoose skills, including data embedding, data referencing, aggregation pipelines, virtual population and query middleware etc.
- FraghQL: used Apollo on both frontend and backend. Able to integrate Apollo as an Express middleware, and replace the traditional REST APIs with GraphQL. Code example: https://github.com/XiaozhouCui/nextjs-portfolio
- Angular: I made several personal projects using Angular 10, familiar with TypeScript, @angular/core, RxJs, Services and Dependency Injection. Example: https://emailclient-peach.vercel.app/
- Solid foundation in basic web development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery etc.
- Familia with traditional LAMP stack: spent a year working with PHP and MySQL during my diploma study. Old project: https://www.joesdemosite.com/wdv/index.php
- Version control: Refer to my GitHub account at the top of this CV. Source code of all my personal projects can be found there.
- Agile experience: used to work in an Agile team at JR Academy, using Jira (software edition) and Bitbucket for job logging, version control (branching) and code review.

TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS FROM PREVIOUS WORK

- Outstanding problem-solving skills: In my previous engineering design projects, I provided solutions to meet client's needs while spending least money and time.
- Competent communication skills: I chaired many engineering workshops (HAZOP/SIL), coordinating the engineers from oil companies (owners), EPC contractors and vendors.
- Robust time management skills: I always prioritise my workload and able to meet the agreed deadlines for my project tasks.
- Excellent research and analytical skills: Obtained 1st class honours for my Master of Engineering degree (by research), published an academic journal article: *International Journal of Multiphase Flow*, Vol. 36, Issue 10, Pages 836-846
- > Strong adaptability: I lived and worked in China, Australia, New Zealand and Malaysia either as a resident or as an expat.
- ➤ Bilingual, fluent in both English and Chinese. I lived in Australia and New Zealand for 8+ years combined.